<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ResourceCollection>
    <Resource>
        <Title>Collection Administration Help: Introduction</Title>
        <Content><![CDATA[
<h2>Sections</h2>
<p>
<a href="help/collections/customizing_metadata_fields">Customizing Metadata Fields</a><br/>
<a href="help/collections/metadata_field_editor">Metadata Field Editor</a><br/>
<a href="help/metadata/updating_controlled_names">Controlled Names</a><br/>
<a href="help/metadata/updating_option_lists">Option Lists</a><br/>
<a href="help/collections/permissions">Permissions</a><br/>
<a href="help/users/user_access_privilege_flags">Privilege Flags</a><br/>
</p>
<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>The Collection Administration tools are designed to aid in the production,
maintenance, and sharing of item records. At the most basic level, the
information contained in individual item records can be considered data
about data, often called <i>metadata</i>. Metadata is the background information
which describes the content, quality, condition, and other appropriate
characteristics or properties of the items. It allows for the organization,
indexing, and classification of data for storage, discovery, and precise
retrieval by users.</p>

<p>As shipped, the software offers a default set of metadata fields drawn from
the Dublin Core Metadata Element Set
(<abbr title="American National Standards Institute">ANSI</abbr>/<abbr title="National Information Standards Organization">NISO</abbr>
Z39.85-2001), additions from Dublin Core Metadata Initiative
(<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr>) proposals,
<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> recommended
refinements, and three from the Institute of Electrical and Electronics
Engineers
(<abbr title="Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers">IEEE</abbr>)
Learning Object Metadata (<abbr title="Learning Object Metadata">LOM</abbr>)
standard. The <abbr title="Dublin Core">DC</abbr> element set was developed by
the <abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr>, an organization
dedicated to promoting the widespread adoption of interoperable metadata
standards and developing specialized metadata vocabularies for describing
items that enable more intelligent information discovery systems. These
fields are meant to be both broadly applicable and easily understood.</p>

<p>Generally a Dublin Core Metadata Inititative
(<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Inititative">DCMI</abbr>) qualifier can be
either an element refinement or an encoding scheme and helps provide context or
narrow meaning to a metadata value. This can be especially important when
aggregating heterogeneous metadata. Any portal intent on sharing metadata with
other digital library projects or portals should consider qualifying its
metadata.</p>

<p>This software package provides for the qualification of the Dublin Core
metadata fields with encoding schemes. The software is shipped with default
values drawn from DCMI recommendations. Although these
<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Inititative">DCMI</abbr> terms are provided
for convenience, they are not required by the software. The software allows for
the qualification of a particular field both at the metadata field and the
record level. The Qualifier Editor is the first step in this process. Here
administrators specify the encoding scheme and provide the machine readable
specification <abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator">URL</abbr> (as maintained
by <abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Inititative">DCMI</abbr> or other standard
maintenance organization) and namespace.</p>

<p>In order to add and edit records, users must use the work template that is
available from the <a href="index.php?P=EditResource&amp;ID=NEW"><i>Add New
Resource</i></a> and the <i>Edit Resources</i> pages. Initially, each cataloging
record template has this default set of fields available. The default fields
parallel (at a basic level) the structured approach of a library catalog or
commercially available database. The default fields are supplied for convenience
only. Apart from the few required fields, Collection Administrators may disable
and delete fields as needed. For completing these default fields, no particular
cataloging rules, syntax, taxonomy, or other descriptive encoding level are
prescribed or required by the portal software. Organizations are encouraged to
carefully examine organizational cataloging needs and keep them in mind when
establishing which standards, classification schemes, and encoding levels to
follow for portal development. Additionally, organizations that customize the
database should appropriately modify all help texts to reflect the changes.</p>

<p>Collection Administrators may customize the metadata fields as desired using
the <a href="index.php?P=DBEditor">Metadata Field Editor</a>. Why would Portal
Creators want to use the Metadata Field Editor? Most simply, the Metadata Field
Editor allows Collection Administrators the option of creating, editing, and
deleting database fields and their content. For example, if the Collection
Administrator wants to add a database field for the date an item will be
updated in the future, he or she would use the Metadata Field Editor to create a
new date field called <i>Date of Future Update.</i> Display, cataloging
templates, searching, and indexes throughout the portal are automatically
updated after a change is implemented.</p>

<p>The required fields for the Metadata Tool to establish a record are the <i>
<abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator">Url</abbr></i>, <i>Title</i>,
<i>Description</i>, <i>Date Record Checked</i>, <i>Date of Record Creation</i>,
and <i>Release Flag</i>. These fields may not be deleted from the database, the
class type changed, or made optional. In some cases, a default value may be
supplied. In the case of <i>Date of Record Creation</i> and <i>Date Record
Checked</i>, the portal software will supply these dates with the current date
when no other information is given.</p>

<p>The Metadata Tool has special authorization features for components of the
metadata separate from the authorization to add and edit item records to the
database. Because of the nature of Classifications and Names, an organization
may wish to restrict access and editing permission of these two tables within
the database. This permission only applies to adding/editing/deleting
classification or name entries from the database. Unauthorized persons will not
be able to view these options. This authorization is controlled by the system
administrator.</p>

<h2>Qualified Metadata</h2>

<p>This software package provides for the qualification of the Dublin Core
metadata fields by encoding schemes and element refinements. These features
offer additional information regarding the metadata value and provides context
for that value when sharing metadata. Portal software handles encoding schemes
differently than element refinements. An example of an encoding scheme,
qualifying Classification with the Dewey Decimal Classification
(<abbr title="Dewey Decimal Classification">DDC</abbr>) informs of a particular
value for Classification and that value is to be interpreted within the
<abbr title="Dewey Decimal Classification">DDC</abbr> realm vs. other similar
schemes. An element refinement example would be a more specific Date such as
Date Submitted or Date Copyrighted.</p>

<p>The portal software is shipped with default encoding scheme values drawn from
Dublin Core Metadata Inititative
(<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr>) recommendations.
These <abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> recognized
encoding schemes are provided for convenience. To make use of the metadata
qualifying features, portal Administrators must define (in the Administration
section) whether a metadata field uses encoding schemes and at what level
(record or field level). They are not required by the software either at the
metadata field or the record level.</p>

<p>Item Level Qualifiers means that a particular field could possibly have more
than one possible encoding scheme. For example, drawing upon both Library of
Congress Subject Headings
(<abbr title="Library of Congress Subject Headings">LCSH</abbr>) and the
National Library of Medicine's Medical Subject Headings
(<abbr title="National Library of Medicine's Medical Subject Headings">MeSH</abbr>)
vocabularies for Subject. Resource editors, when completing a item record in
the Metadata Tool, then choose between the allowed qualifying values provided to
them by the portal Administrator. The scheme name will appear next the the value
in the metadata record. For option lists (for example, <i>Resource Type</i>) encoding
schemes are selected when added to a list of Metadata Tool Options. The
alternative to item level is for a metadata field to be refined at the field
level, in other words, any particular metadata field within a given portal uses
the same qualifier. One qualifying encoding scheme can be selected as a default
by the Administrator. This is the value the software will supply when no value
is selected by the editor.</p>

<p><abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> recommended element
refinement fields are handled differently by portal software. As the software is
shipped, these are supplied as default metadata fields. To make use of these
Collection Administrators should enable all desired fields on the
<a href="index.php?P=DBEditor"><i>Metadata Field Editor</i></a> page.</p>

<p><abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> recommended
refinements share meaning with the
<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> simple elements but
have narrower semantic properties. For example, <i>Title</i> and <i>Alternate
Title</i> share meaning, but <i>Alternate Title</i> is more specific
interpretation. The portal software handles refinements differently than
qualifying with encoding schemes.
<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> recommended element
refinements are supplied as metadata fields. These fields in the
<abbr title="Open Archives Initiative">OAI</abbr> harvested metadata portal
software will give the correct
<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> tags with
corresponding <abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr>
<abbr title="Uniform Resource Identifier">URI</abbr>(s). This is also the case
for the three Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers
(<abbr title="Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers">IEEE</abbr>)
Learning Object Metadata (<abbr title="Learning Object Metadata">LOM</abbr>)
and the <abbr title="Dublin Core">DC</abbr> Education Working Group recommended
fields.</p>

<p><strong>Note</strong>: Presently the Import,
<abbr title="Rich Site Summary">RSS</abbr>, and manual export functions do not
support <abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> Qualifiers.
Qualified metadata is supported in
<abbr title="Open Archives Initiative">OAI</abbr> harvesting at this time.</p>

<p>For an up-to-date specification of all metadata terms maintained by the
Dublin Core Metadata Initiative, including elements, element refinements,
encoding schemes, and vocabulary terms (for example,
<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> Type Vocabulary) see
the <a href="https://www.dublincore.org/specifications/dublin-core/dcmi-terms/"><i>
<abbr title="Dublin Core Metadata Initiative">DCMI</abbr> Metadata Terms</i></a>
document. A basic discussion of the application of the Dublin Core Element Set
is the <a href="https://www.dublincore.org/resources/userguide/">Dublin Core
<i>User Guide</i></a>.</p>]]>
        </Content>
		<CleanURL>help/collections</CleanURL>
    </Resource>
    <Resource>
    	<Title>Collection Administration Help: Customizing Metadata Fields</Title>
        <Content><![CDATA[<h2>Customizing Metadata Fields</h2>

<p>Collection Administrators can customize the database's metadata fields by
adding new fields, editing existing fields, or deleting unnecessary fields.
Portal developers are strongly encouraged to evaluate their metadata and
cataloging needs before populating the portal item database. The use of
existing standards, vocabularies, and rules is likewise encouraged.</p>

<p>To customize a metadata field, administrators must define the characteristics
of the field and its functionality. These customizations will be automatically
propagated throughout the search engines, displays, and metadata cataloging
templates. After extensive alterations to the metadata schema, administrators
may be required to <a href="index.php?P=ConfirmRebuildSearchDB">rebuild the
search database</a> and <a href="index.php?P=ConfirmRebuildRecommenderDB">
rebuild the recommender database</a>.</p>

<p>When adding a new field, ensure that <i>Hide Disabled Fields</i> is unchecked
in order to assess whether a standard field already exists and can be enabled
for use. If no existing field can be found, administrators may wish to add a new
field. To do so, click the <kbd><samp>Add New Field</samp></kbd> button at the
top of the <a href="index.php?P=DBEditor"><i>Metadata Field Editor</i></a> page.
Newly created <i>Text</i>, <i>Paragraph</i>, <i>Number</i> and <i>Flag</i>
fields, when enabled, are immediately appended to all existing item records.
For individual records, the default value may be overwritten or edited using the
Edit Resource functions. The field also will appear immediately on the Metadata
Tool cataloging template. The corresponding default value is written into the
item record if no other value is specified.</p> <p>To edit an existing
metadata field, click the name of the field to be edited, make the necessary
changes, and click the <kbd><samp>Update Field</samp></kbd> button.</p>

<p>Due to conflicts of functionality between field types, changing existing
fields between types is constrained to limit data loss. <i>Text</i>,
<i>Paragraph</i>, <i>Flag</i>, and <i>Number</i> fields are interchangeable.
<i>Option</i>, <i>Controlled Name</i>, and <i>Tree</i> fields are interchangeable. <i>Date</i>
fields can be changed to <i>Text</i> fields.</p> <p>To delete an existing
metadata field, click the name of the field to be removed and click the
<kbd><samp>Delete Field</samp></kbd> button.</p> <p>The only field required to
establish an item record is the field designated as the Resource Title Field
in the <a href="index.php?P=SysConfig">System Configuration</a>, a required
setting. Fields designated as Resource
<abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator">URL</abbr>, Resource Screenshot, Resource
File, and Resource Description in the System Configuration also cannot be
deleted from the database, but those values need not be set.</p> <h3>Metadata
Field Types</h3> <p>The most fundamental attribute of a field is its type. There
are 17 types or classes of fields. The field types include:</p>

<h4>Text</h4>

<p>This field is a free text field. Portal software default metadata field
examples for this type include: <i>Title</i>, <i>Alternate Title</i>,
<i><abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator">Url</abbr></i>, <i>Source</i>,
<i>Relation</i>, <i>Coverage</i>, and <i>Rights</i>. Limited
<abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr> tags are permitted to
increase visual appeal in the <i>Text</i> field types. The allowable
<abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr> tags include the following:
bold <code>&lt;b&gt;</code>, italics <code>&lt;i&gt;</code>, underline
<code>&lt;u&gt;</code>, strike <code>&lt;s&gt;</code>, anchor
<code>&lt;a&gt;</code>, superscript <code>&lt;sup&gt;</code>, subscript
<code>&lt;sub&gt;</code>, paragraph <code>&lt;p&gt;</code>, quote
<code>&lt;q&gt;</code>, and preformatted text <code>&lt;pre&gt;</code>. Any
break <code>&lt;br&gt;</code> tags or other unsupported
<abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr> tag in <i>Text</i> fields
will be stripped after adding or updating the record in the Metadata Tool. All
<abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr> tags will be stripped from
metadata harvested via <abbr title="Rich Site Summary">RSS</abbr> and
<abbr title="Open Archives Initiative">OAI</abbr>.</p>

<h4>Paragraph</h4>

<p>This field is a free text field for block of text. The portal software
default metadata field example for this type is the <i>Description</i>. Limited
<abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr> tags are permitted to
increase visual appeal in the <i>Paragraph</i> field types. The allowable
<abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr> tags include the following:
bold <code>&lt;b&gt;</code>, italics <code>&lt;i&gt;</code>, underline
<code>&lt;u&gt;</code>, strike <code>&lt;s&gt;</code>, anchor
<code>&lt;a&gt;</code>, superscript <code>&lt;sup&gt;</code>, subscript
<code>&lt;sub&gt;</code>, paragraph <code>&lt;p&gt;</code>, quote
<code>&lt;q&gt;</code>, preformatted text <code>&lt;pre&gt;</code>, and break
<code>&lt;br&gt;</code>. All <abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr>
tags will be stripped from metadata harvested via
<abbr title="Rich Site Summary">RSS</abbr> and
<abbr title="Open Archives Initiative">OAI</abbr>.</p>

<h4>Number</h4>

<p>The number field provides for a whole number. The portal software default
example is the <i>Cumulative Rating</i>.</p>

<h4>Date</h4>

<p>This field records a date in a standard format. Users do not need to enter
the date in this format. The software will translate a provided date into the
standard format (<i>YYYY-MM-DD</i>). For instance, if one enters <i>January 6,
2001</i> the date is stored as <i>2001-01-06</i>. An example of this
field type in the default schema is <i>Date Issued</i>. For
searching purposes, this field type can be searched in the field search on the
<a href="index.php?P=AdvancedSearch"><i>Advanced Search</i></a> page.</p>

<h4>Timestamp</h4>

<p>This field is intended for recording a specific date and time.  Like
the <i>Date</i> field type, values may be entered in an array of common
formats and will be automatically normalized to a standard format.
An example of this field type in the default schema is <i>Date Record
Checked</i>.</p>

<h4>Flag</h4>

<p>This field allows for toggled values (<i>Yes</i>/<i>No</i>, <i>On</i>/
<i>Off</i>, etc.). A portal software default example is the <i>Release Flag</i>.
The <i>Release Flag</i> does not appear to the public either in a full record
display or the Advanced Search. It appears as a search option in the Metadata
Tool. Newly created <i>Flag</i> type fields, when enabled, will be searchable
via the Advanced Search and the Metadata Tool Search. <i>Flag</i> fields cannot
be optional.</p> <h4>Tree</h4> <p><i>Tree</i> fields allow for the use of an
existing standard classification schema or your organization's homegrown
taxonomy. A tree field in the portal provides users with a way of browsing
through the items in hierarchical tiers. This approach guides users
unfamiliar with terminology to appropriate items descending in complexity
from simple to more precise. Privilege to build or edit the vocabulary or
taxonomy of classifications requires authorization from the collection
administrator. The <i>Classification</i> field is an example of a tree field.</p>

<h4>Controlled Name</h4>

<p>This field type allows for the central control of names and vocabularies.
Many persons or entities are known by multiple names, or have names that take
multiple forms (e.g. <i>IBM</i>, <i>International Business Machines</i>, <i>IBM
Inc.</i>, etc.). A Controlled Name designates a single official name for that
entity within the database. The Variant Names are other names, or forms of
names, associated with that entity. These may include acronyms, names with
honorary titles included, dropped initials, diminutives, etc.</p>

<p>Having both a Controlled Name and Variant Names allows all records associated
with a single entity to be linked. Editing names is also simplified by requiring
only one central edit. The ability to add variants makes it possible to retrieve
those name forms when searching records. Edits to the Controlled Name
will be propagated to all associated records bearing Variant Names. Portal
software default examples for this field are <i>Publisher</i>, <i>Creator</i>,
and <i>Subject</i>.</p> <h4>Option</h4> <p><i>Option</i> fields are most useful
when a limited number of thematically related terms are needed to describe an
item. These fields provide Limit options in the Advanced Search. Examples of
this field type from the portal software default metadata fields are
<i>Audience</i>, <i>Resource Type</i>, and <i>Language</i>. Options can be
modified through the <a href="index.php?P=EditOptionList"><i>Edit Option
Lists</i></a> page.</p> <h4>User Fields</h4> <p><i>User</i> fields record the
user account that adds or modifies an item. Some user fields are required by
the portal system and may not be modified.</p>

<h4>Image</h4>

<p>Images of .jpg, .gif, and .bmp file types may be added to the record for
illustration or other purposes. File selection begins using the
<kbd><samp>Choose File</samp></kbd> button found to the right of field. After
selecting the image, the file name will automatically be added to the item
record. To complete the process, click on the <kbd><samp>Upload
Image</samp></kbd> button. A small image (thumbnail) will appear within the
item record.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>After an image has been added to a record
      a <kbd><samp>Delete</samp></kbd> button will appear. To remove an image
      already associated with an item record simply click on this button. The
      desired image should then be deleted from the item record.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Collection administrators are strongly encouraged to complete
      the <i>Description</i> field when adding images to an
      item record. It provides explanatory text for images and follows
      well-established guidelines for accessibility. It is essential for users
      who have vision disabilities and those using screen reader software.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Additionally, the <i>Description</i> field provides text that can
      be searched (when enabled by Collection Administrators) by the Keyword,
      Advanced Search, and Metadata Tool search engine.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4>File</h4>

<p>A <i>File</i> field allows an electronic file to be uploaded from the user's
computer directly into the item record.</p>

<h4><abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator">Url</abbr></h4>

<p>A <i><abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator">Url</abbr></i> field points to a
web address that either contains the full version of the information described
in the item record, or contains other pertinent information or metadata for
the record.</p>

<h4>Point</h4>

<p>A <i>Point</i> field allows a point in any two-dimensional coordinate system,
e.g., the latitude and longitude of a location on a map, to be associated with an
item record.</p>

<h4>Reference</h4>

<p>A <i>Reference</i> field allows Collection Administrators to associate one or
more item records with another item record. The values of
<i>Reference</i> fields appear as links to the full record of an item.</p>

<h3>Other Considerations</h3>

<p>After considering the function of a desired metadata field and selecting form
the list above, other considerations must be made. Each field must be given
attributes in four different areas: <b>Basic Information</b>, <b>Qualifiers</b>,
<b>Type Specific Information</b>, and <b>Privileges</b>. These attributes
are:</p>

<h4>Basic Information</h4>

<dl>
  <dt>Name</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) A clear, easily understood label.</p></dd>

  <dt>Display Name</dt>
  <dd><p>The name displayed to users, if different from the Name.</p></dd>

  <dt>Definition</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) A statement of explanation, meaning, intent and
      scope.</p></dd>

  <dt>Instructions</dt>
  <dd><p>Allows administrators to give instructions, guidelines, or best
      practices for the cataloging of the field.  The Instructions are visible
      from the Edit/Add Resource page when the mouse is hovered over the field
      Name.</p></dd>

  <dt>Enabled</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; determines if the field is actively in use.</p></dd>

  <dt>Editable</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; determines if the data in the field can be edited.</p></dd>

  <dt>Optional</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; determines if data is required in the field or if that data is
    optional.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h4>Qualifiers</h4>

<dl>
  <dt>Uses Qualifiers</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; determines whether a particular field will make use of
      qualifiers. If an administrator answers <i>Yes</i>, but fails to specify
      further information below, no metadata will be refined.</p></dd>

  <dt>Has Item Level Qualifiers</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; determines whether the field qualified at the item level or
      not. Selecting <i>Yes</i> means that a particular field may have more than
      one encoding scheme. Resource editors when completing an item record
      then choose between all possible qualifier values provided to them by the
      Collection Administrator. Selecting <i>No</i> means the metadata field is
      qualified at the field level, and any data within that field uses the same
      encoding scheme.</p></dd>

  <dt>Allowed Qualifiers</dt>
  <dd><p>List of encoding schemes a Collection Administrator permits for a given
      metadata field. This box is populated by the Qualifier Editor. Multiple
      qualifiers can be selected by holding the command button (for Mac) or
      control button (for Windows) and clicking the desired
      qualifiers. <strong>Note</strong>: Removing an item from this list may
      result in a loss of data.</p></dd>

  <dt>Default Qualifier</dt>
  <dd><p>One encoding scheme is selected as a default. This is the value the
      software will supply when no value is selected by the item
      editor.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h4>Search</h4>

<dl>
  <dt>Include in Keyword Search</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; determines if the field should be included among fields
      searched for keywords, either by the Keyword Search function at the top of
      every page, or the fielded Keyword search on the Advanced Search.</p></dd>

  <dt>Include in Advanced Search</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; determines if the field should be included among fields
      available in Advanced Search and Limits.</p></dd>

  <dt>Include in Faceted Search</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; determines if the field should be included among fields
      available in the faceted search interface.</p></dd>

  <dt>Include in Sort Options</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; determines if the field should be included in the list of
      options by which users may sort search results.</p></dd>

  <dt>Search Weight</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) 1-20; determines the importance relative to other searched
      fields in search results. The search weight must be set to be greater than
      zero to have an affect on keyword searches. The default values for the
      portal software as shipped are <i>Title</i>=5, <i>Alternate Title</i>=3,
      <i>Description</i>=1, Controlled Names (<i>Subject</i>, <i>Publisher</i>,
      and <i>Creator</i>)=3. The higher the number, the more important to search
      relevance the field is.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h4>Type-Specific Information</h4>

<h5>Text</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Field Size</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Defines the display size of the text box in number of
      characters.</p></dd>

  <dt>Max Length</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Defines the total length of text available for data entry in
      number of characters.</p></dd>

  <dt>Allow <abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr> in Text</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; describes if basic HTML tags are allowed in the text of the
      field.</p></dd>

  <dt>Default Value</dt>
  <dd><p>Content of field if no other value entered.</p></dd>
<dl>

<h5>Paragraph</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Paragraph Rows</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Defines the total length of text available to enter
      data.</p></dd>

  <dt>Paragraph Columns</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Defines the total height of text available to enter
      data.</p></dd>

  <dt>Allow <abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr> in Text</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; describes if basic HTML tags are allowed in the text of the
      field.</p></dd>

  <dt>Use <abbr title="What You See Is What You Get">WYSIWYG</abbr> Editor</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No when <i>Allow
      <abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr> in Text</i> is set
      to <i>Yes</i>; describes if word-processor style buttons are available to
      user when adding or editing text in the field.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h5>Number</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Field Size</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Defines the total space of text available to enter
      data.</p></dd>

  <dt>Minimum Value</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Smallest positive whole number allowed.</p></dd>

  <dt>Maximum Value</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Largest positive whole number allowed.</p></dd>

  <dt>Default Value</dt>
  <dd><p>Content of field if no other value entered.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h5>Date</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Field Size</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Defines the total length of text available to enter
      data.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h5>Timestamp</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Update Method</dt>
  <dd><p>The rules for when or if the timestamp in the field is
      updated.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h5>Flag</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Flag On Label</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) The display value when the flag is set to
      <i>On</i>.</p></dd>

  <dt>Flag Off Label</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) The display value when the flag is set to
      <i>Off</i>.</p></dd>

  <dt>Default Value</dt>
  <dd><p>On/Off; content of field if no other value entered.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h5>Option</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Allow Multiple</dt>
  <dd><p>Yes/No; defines if multiple values an be entered for an option
      field.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h5>User</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Restrict to Users With One of the Following</dt>
  <dd><p>Defines the user privilege level or custom privilege flag needed on a
      user account to display that username in the list of possible users to
      choose from.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h5>Image</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Default Alt Text</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Text that will display when the image cannot be viewed or
      when image is scanned by assistive devices.</p></dd>

  <dt>Max Height</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) The maximum height for the full display of the
      image.</p></dd>

  <dt>Max Width</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) The maximum width for the full display of the
      image.</p></dd>

  <dt>Max Preview Height</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) The maximum height for the display of the image in the full
      record page.</p></dd>

  <dt>Max Preview Width</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) The maximum width for the display of the image in the full
      record page.</p></dd>

  <dt>Max Thumbnail Height</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) The maximum height for the display of the image thumbnail in
      search results, browse items, and new items displays.</p></dd>

  <dt>Max Thumbnail Width</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) The maximum width for the display of the image thumbnail in
      search results, browse items, and new items displays.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h5><abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator">Url</abbr></h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Field Size</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Defines in number of characters and the display size of the
      text box.</p></dd>

  <dt>Max Length</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Defines in number of characters and the total length of text
      available for data entry.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h5>Point</h5>

<dl>
  <dt>Field Size</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Defines in number of characters and the display size of the
      text box.</p></dd>

  <dt>Point Precision</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Determines how many digits should be allowed to the left of
      the decimal point for both values.</p></dd>

  <dt>Decimal Digits in Point</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required) Determines how many digits should be allowed to the right of
      the decimal point for both values</p></dd>
</dl>

<h4>Resource Editing</h4>

<dl>
  <dt>Option List Field Threshold</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required for <i>Tree</i> and <i>Controlled Name</i> Fields only) The
      number of possible values for the metadata field at which the form field
      used to modify the value changes from checkboxes to option lists.</p></dd>
  <dt>Incremental Search Field Threshold</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required for <i>Tree</i> and <i>Controlled Name</i> Fields only) The
      number of possible values for the metadata field at which the form field
      used to modify the value changes from option lists to an incremental
      search field.</p></dd>
  <dt>Max Number of Search Results</dt>
  <dd><p>(Required for <i>Tree</i>, <i>Controlled Name</i>, and <i>Reference</i>
      Fields only) The maximum number of displayed results when the tree field's
      vocabulary is searched.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h4><abbr title="Open Archives Initiative">OAI</abbr></h4>

<dl>
  <dt>Use for <abbr title="Open Archives Intiative">OAI</abbr> Sets</dt>
  <dd><p>(For <i>Tree</i>, <i>Controlled Name</i>, and <i>Option Fields</i>
      only) Yes/No; determines if the value in the field can be used to define
      sets for <abbr title="Open Archives Intiative">OAI</abbr>
      harvesting.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h4>Privileges</h4>

<dl>
  <dt>Privilege Required for Viewing</dt>
  <dd><p>The privilege level, custom privilege flag, and/or user value required
      to view the data contained in the field.</p></dd>

  <dt>Privilege Required for Editing</dt>
  <dd><p>The privilege level, custom privilege flag, and/or user value required
      to edit the data contained in the field.</p></dd>

  <dt>Privilege Required for Authoring</dt>
  <dd><p>The privilege level, custom privilege flag, and/or user value required
      to add data to the field.</p></dd>

  <dt>Privilege Required for Browsing (<i>Tree</i> Fields Only)</dt>
  <dd><p>The privilege level, custom privilege flag, and/or user value required
      for the field to display on the Browse Resources page.</p></dd>

  <dt>Privilege Required to View Full Image (<i>Image</i> Fields Only)</dt>
  <dd><p>The privilege level, custom privilege flag, and/or user value required
      to view the full size image uploaded in the field.</p></dd>
</dl>

<h3>Important Reminder</h3>

<p>After customizing the database configuration,
Administrators are reminded to reflect these changes in the appropriate Help
texts. Since these help texts guide and instruct portal users in use, searching,
and maintenance, every effort should be made to accurately guide and educate
users as to portal features.</p>]]>
		</Content>
        <CleanURL>help/collections/customizing_metadata_fields</CleanURL>
    </Resource>
    <Resource>
    	<Title>Collection Administration Help: Metadata Field Editor</Title>
    	<Content><![CDATA[<h2>Metadata Field Editor</h2>

<p>The Metadata Field Editor is designed to customize the item database and
metadata structure. Metadata is the background information which describes the
content, quality, condition, and other appropriate characteristics of the
item. At the most basic level, this information can be considered data about
data. It allows for the organization, indexing, and classification of data for
storage, discovery, and precise retrieval by users. The set of chosen metadata
fields for a particular collection is a called <i>Metadata Schema</i>.</p>

<p>The Metadata Field Editor allows System and Collection Administrators to
create, edit, and delete database fields and their content. For example, if the
System Administrator wants to add a database field for the date an item will
be updated in the future, the System Administrator would use the Metadata Field
Editor to create a new <i>Date</i> field called <i>Date of Future Update</i>.</p>

<p>The default fields parallel (at a basic level) the structured approach one
find in a library catalog or commercially available database. For completing
these default fields, no particular cataloging rules, syntax, taxonomy, or other
descriptive encoding level are prescribed or required. Organizations are
encouraged to carefully examine organizational cataloging needs and keep them in
mind when establishing which standards, classification schemes, and encoding
levels to follow in the application of
Metavus for portal development.</p>

<p>The configuration of metadata for individual fields can largely be broken out
into four categories: <b>Metadata</b>, <b>Display</b>, <b>Access</b>, and
<b>Search</b>. On the <a href="index.php?P=DBEditor"><i>Metadata Field
Editor</i></a> page, a summary for each of these sections is listed in a tabbed
interface. By default, disabled metadata fields are hidden. Uncheck the <i>Hide
Disabled Fields</i> box to display all metadata fields available.</p>

<h3>Metadata</h3>

<p>Separated by field type, this tab displays the field name and the
configuration of its metadata attributes: <i>Editable</i>, <i>Optional</i>,
<i>Default Value</i>, <i>Allow Multiple</i>, <i>Uses Qualifiers</i>,
<i>Item-Level Qualifiers</i>, and <i>Default Qualifiers</i>. Click on any field
name or the <kbd><samp>Edit</samp></kbd> button to the far right to add or
change the field metadata configurations. <strong>Note</strong>: All attributes
listed do not apply to all fields.</p> <h3>Display</h3> <p>Separated by field
type, this tab displays the field name and how that field is displayed to users:
<i>Field Size</i>, <i>Max Length</i>, <i>Allow
<abbr title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML</abbr></i>, and <i>Max Number of
Search Results</i>. Click on any field name or the <kbd><samp>Edit</samp></kbd>
button to the far right to add or change the field's display configurations.
<strong>Note</strong>: All attributes listed do not apply to all fields.</p>

<h3>Access</h3>

<p>Separated by field type, this tab displays the field name and how access and
privileges required for that field are configured: <i>Full Image Privilege</i>,
<i>Browsing Privilege</i>, <i>Viewing Privilege</i>, <i>Authoring Privilege</i>,
and <i>Editing Privilege</i>. Click on any field name or the
<kbd><samp>Edit</samp></kbd> button to the far right to add or change the
field's access configuration. <strong>Note</strong>: All attributes listed do
not apply to all fields.</p> <h3>Search</h3> <p>Separated by field type, this
tab displays the field name and how its search functionality is configured:
<i>Include in Keyword Search</i>, <i>Include in Advanced Search</i>, <i>Include
in Sort Options</i>, and <i>Search Weight</i>. Click on any field name or the
<kbd><samp>Edit</samp></kbd> button to the far right to add or change the
field's search configuration. <strong>Note</strong>: All attributes listed do
not apply to all fields.</p>]]>
		</Content>
    	<CleanURL>help/collections/metadata_field_editor</CleanURL>
    </Resource>
    <Resource>
    	<Title>Collection Administration Help: Permissions and Access Control</Title>
    	<Content><![CDATA[<h1>Permissions and Access Control</h1>

<p>The permissions system in Metavus determines who can create, edit, and view
items.</p>

<p>In Metavus, <b>Authoring</b> refers to the creation of new items,
<b>Editing</b> refers to the modification of existing items, and
<b>Viewing</b> refers to the display of items.</p>

<h2>How Permissions are Applied</h2>

<p>This system works in two levels: <b>Schema permissions</b> and
<b>field permissions</b>. The schema permissions establish minimum
requirements that apply to all fields. Field permissions can be used
to provide additional restrictions for specific fields beyond what the
schema requires. Note that for each field, Metavus first evaluates the
schema permissions and <i>only if those requirements are satisfied</i>
does it proceed to check the field permissions.</p>

<p>For your reference, schema permissions are repeated on the Editing
page for each metadata field, along with an 'edit' button to modify
the schema permissions. Any changes to schema permissions will apply
to all fields from that schema, not just to the field you were editing
when the 'edit' button was clicked.</p>

<h2>Conditions Used in Permissions</h2>

<p>Each authoring/editing/viewing permission is made up of a series of
conditions, combined with a logical operator, which must be satisfied
to perform the corresponding action. Each condition may be either a
check against item field values, a check of user privilege flags,
or a condition subgroup containing its own logical operator.</p>

<p>In contexts where no one specific item can provide values for
evaluating conditions, checks against item field values will be
considered satisfied if the collection contains any items that
could satisfy them. For example, on the Advanced Search page, no
items are displayed. Therefore, there is no one specific item
to use for privilege checks on that page. So, a condition like
&quot;Language is English&quot; will be satisfied if the collection
contains any items where the <i>Language</i> is &quot;English&quot.</p>

<h2>Example Viewing Permissions</h2>

<p>An examination of the default Viewing permissions illustrates how the system
works:</p>

<table>
  <tr>
    <td class="cw-help-paragraph">Top level logic: OR</td>
    <td>Conditions will all be ORed together (satisfying any one of
      them is sufficient to satisfy the requirements).</td>
  </tr><tr>
    <td class="cw-help-paragraph">Current user has <i>Master
        Resource Administrator</i> privilege</td>
    <td>All users having 'Master Resource Administrator' are able to
      view all fields, unless the field specifies further
      restrictions.</td>
  </tr><tr>
    <td class="cw-help-paragraph"><i>Record Status</i> contains &quot;Published&quot;</td>
    <td>All fields on any item marked Published should be
      viewable, unless the field specifies further restrictions.
      Note that this check is skipped when there is not a specific
      item to check (e.g., on the Advanced Search page).
    </td>
  </tr><tr>
    <td class="cw-help-paragraph">( Top level logic: AND </td>
    <td>Begin a new privilege subgroup where conditions are ANDed
      together (all conditions are required in order to satisfy the
      subgroup).  This subgroup allows all users having <i>Personal
      Resource Administrator</i> to view any field on items for
      which their user account is the value of the 'Added By Id'
      metadata field.</td>
  </tr><tr>
    <td class="cw-help-paragraph mv-indented-help">
      Added By Id is Current User
    </td>
    <td> </td>
  </tr><tr>
    <td class="cw-help-paragraph">)</td>
    <td> End the privilege subgroup.</td>
  </tr>
</table>

<h2>Advanced Example: sub-collections</h2>

<p>Suppose you manage a collection to be used for both public
items and private instructional materials.  There are two kinds
of private instructional materials, assignments and answer keys,
along with three kinds of users: students, teaching assistants, and
instructors.  Students should only be able to view the assignments,
teaching assistants should be able to view both types, and
instructors should be able to edit answer keys and assignments but
not public items.</p>

<p>To accomplish this, you'll first create
<a href="index.php?P=EditPrivilegeNames">Custom Privilege Flags</a> for each of
your three user types. Then, you'll use <i><a href="index.php?P=EditOptionList">
Edit Option Lists</a></i> to update <i>Resource Type</i> to include your material
types (i.e. assignment and answer key) along with 'Public'.

<p>Then, configure the following Schema-level <b>viewing</b> privileges:</p>
<div>
    <i>Current User</i> has Master Resource Administrator privilege OR <br/>(
    <div style="margin-left: 4em;">
      <i>Record Status</i> contains &quot;Published&quot; AND <br/> (
      <div style="margin-left: 4em;">
        <i>Resource Type</i> is Public OR <br/> (
        <div style="margin-left: 4em;">
          <i>Resource Type</i> is Assignment AND <br/>
          <i>Current User</i> has Student privilege
        </div>) <br/> OR <br/>(
        <div style="margin-left: 4em;">
          <i>Resource Type</i> is Answer Key AND <br/> (
          <div style="margin-left: 4em;">
            <i>Current User</i> has Teaching Assistant privilege OR <br/>
            <i>Current User</i> has Instructor privilege
          </div>)
        </div>)
      </div>)
    </div>)
</div>

<p>The corresponding schema-level <b>editing</b> privileges would then be:</p>

<div>
    <i>Current User</i> has Master Resource Administrator privilege OR <br/>(
     <div style="margin-left: 4em;">
     <i>Current User</i> has Instructor privilege AND <br/>
     <i>Release Flag</i> is true AND <br/> (
     <div style="margin-left: 4em;">
       <i>Resource Type</i> is Assignment OR <br/>
       <i>Resource Type</i> is Answer Key
     </div>)
   </div>)
</div>]]>
		</Content>
    	<CleanURL>help/collections/permissions</CleanURL>
    </Resource>
    <Resource>
    	<Title>Metadata Tool Help: Updating Controlled Names</Title>
    	<Content><![CDATA[<h2>Updating Controlled Names</h2>

<p>Controlled Names allow for the central control of proper individual or
institutional names and vocabularies. Many persons or entities are known by
multiple names, or have names that take multiple forms (e.g. <i>IBM</i>,
<i>International Business Machines</i>, <i>IBM Inc.</i>, etc.). A Controlled
Name designates a single official name for that entity within the database. The
Variant Names are other names, or forms of names, associated with that
entity. These include acronyms, names with honorary titles included, dropped
initials, diminutives, etc.</p>

<p>The Metadata Tool allows Collection Administrators to add, update, and delete
controlled names and has special authorization features for components of the
metadata separate from the authorization to add/edit item records. Because
of the complex nature of Controlled Names, an organization may wish to restrict
access and editing or deleting permission within the database. This
authorization is controlled by the Collection Administrator.</p>

<p>This section details the procedures for updating Controlled Names.
Edits and corrections appear immediately in each associated record. To add,
update, or delete a Controlled Name:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><a href="index.php?P=Login">Log in</a> to the portal with an authorized
    account and then go to the <a href="index.php?P=EditControlledName"><i>Edit
    Controlled Names</i></a> page.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Search for a name or a list of names by entering the name into the search
    box and clicking the <kbd><samp>Search</samp></kbd> button for the
    appropriate field (<i>Publisher</i>, <i>Creator</i>, etc.). Searches will
    return matches from the Controlled Name and the Variant Name fields. The
    Variant Name is searched here to allow Collection Administrators to record name
    variations and add flexibility to the Controlled Name feature. Multiple
    entries are allowed within the Variant Name field. It is recommended
    practice to use a semi-colon to separate the distinct values of Variant
    Names.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The Metadata Tool will generate a list of results matching the
    search. Edit every entry desired, and the Metadata Tool will update all
    entries simultaneously and propagate changes to associated item
    records.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A Controlled Name can be remapped to another existing Controlled
    Name. For instance, <i>University of Wisconsin, Madison</i> can be remapped
    to <i>University of Wisconsin - Madison</i> if the latter already exists as
    a controlled name. Type in the Controlled Name you wish to map to, and click
    the <kbd><samp>Save Changes</samp></kbd> button. This will change all
    instances of the Controlled Name in question to the new one, and present
    users with a list of records that were altered.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>To delete any names from the database, check the box to the left and
    click the <kbd><samp>Save Changes</samp></kbd> button. The name(s) will be
    removed from all associated records and present users with a list of records
    that were altered.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]>
		</Content>
    	<CleanURL>help/metadata/updating_controlled_names</CleanURL>
    </Resource>
    <Resource>
    	<Title>Metadata Tool Help: Updating Option Lists</Title>
    	<Content><![CDATA[<h2>Updating Option Lists</h2>

<p>Options are the standardized list of possible terms for <i>Option</i>
metadata fields. <i>Option</i> fields are most useful when a limited number of
thematically related terms are needed to describe an item. After the field is
created using the <a href="help/collections/metadata_field_editor">Metadata Field
Editor</a>, the vocabulary can then be added, edited, or deleted from the
Metadata Tool's <a href="index.php?P=EditOptionList"><i>Edit Option
Lists</i></a> page. These fields provide Limit options in the Advanced Search
engine. Examples of this class of fields from the portal software default
metadata fields are the <i>Audience</i>, <i>Resource Type</i>, and
<i>Language</i> field. Options can be modified through the
<a href="index.php?P=EditOptionList"><i>Edit Option Lists</i></a> page. To
add, edit, remap, delete, or set default Options:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><a href="index.php?P=Login">Log in</a> to the portal with an authorized
    account and then go to the
    <a href="index.php?P=EditOptionList"><i>Edit Option Lists</i></a> page.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Select the appropriate field.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>To add an Option, select the <i>Add New Option</i> box and type the
    option in the space provided. Click the <kbd><samp>Save Changes</samp></kbd>
    button.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>To edit an Option, find the appropriate one and update it. Click the
    <kbd><samp>Save Changes</samp></kbd> button.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>To delete an Option, find the appropriate one and select the
    <i>Delete</i> box to the right. Click the <kbd><samp>Save
    Changes</samp></kbd> button.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>To remap an Option, find the appropriate one and select the <i>Remap
    To</i> radio button, followed by the appropriate Option in the box
    provided. Click the <kbd><samp>Save Changes</samp></kbd> button.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>To set a default Option, find the appropriate one and place a check mark
    in the box furthest to the left. Click the <kbd><samp>Save
    Changes</samp></kbd> button.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>When changes are made, the <a href="index.php?P=EditOptionList"><i>Edit
Option List</i></a> page appears with a summary of the changes.</p>]]>
		</Content>
    	<CleanURL>help/metadata/updating_option_lists</CleanURL>
    </Resource>
    <Resource>
    	<Title>User Administration Help: User Access Privilege Flags</Title>
    	<Content><![CDATA[<h2>User Access Privilege Flags</h2>

<p>There are 12 default access privilege flags. These privilege flags allow
system administrators to assign different types of work to different users. This
allows an organization the flexibility to create the most efficient and
practical workflow possible for its needs. The ability to disperse the workflow
across individuals allows project managers to create discrete tasks in the
workflow as needed, which is particularly useful for projects located in more
than one geographic location.</p>

<p>For example, System Administrators can designate one or more users to update
the news and announcements section of the home page by giving them the <i>News
Administrator</i> privilege flag. The <i>News Administrator</i> privilege flag
will allow only those users to add news and announcements to the
site. Similarly, System Administrators can designate one or more users to add,
edit, and delete any item records by giving them the <i>Resource
Administrator</i> privilege flag.</p>

<p>Other privilege flags facilitate finer-grained workflows. For example, a
System Administrators could give one or more users the <i>Release Flag
Administrator</i> privilege flag if he or she wants to allow many users to
create item records but doesn't want to make those records publicly viewable
until they are checked and edited.</p>

<p>Privilege flags are assigned by selecting the ones appropriate for the user
being edited (<kbd>Shift</kbd>+<kbd>Click</kbd>) and then clicking
the <kbd><samp>Save Changes</samp></kbd> button. The definitions of the default
access privilege flags are:</p>

<dl>
  <dt><b>Can Post Resource Comments</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may add comments to item records on the site. Resource comments must be enabled for this privilege flag to be useful and new user accounts have this privilege by default, unless the <i>Default New User Privileges</i> setting has been customized.</p></dd>
  <dt><b>Classification Administrator</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may build and maintain the classification taxonomy (e.g., <i>Computers &gt; Hardware &gt; Keyboards &gt; Wireless Keyboards</i>) for the collection.</p></dd>
  <dt><b>Collection Administrator</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may manage the collection, i.e., edit the <abbr title="Open Archives Initiative">OAI</abbr> server settings, export data, modify the metadata schema, etc.</p></dd>
  <dt><b>Controlled Names Administrator</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may create and modify Controlled Name fields, e.g., <i>Publisher</i> and <i>Creator</i>, and are generally responsible for codifying and editing the name forms across the Controlled Name fields.</p></dd>
  <dt><b>Master Resource Administrator</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may edit the metadata records for every item on the site, and are typically in charge of developing, editing, and maintaining the item records in the collection. They are not able to add names or vocabulary to any of the controlled name attribute lists or classification schema.</p></dd>
  <dt><b>News Administrator</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may add and edit the news item announcements that are displayed on the home page.</p></dd>
  <dt><b>Personal Resource Administrator</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may create item records but only edit the ones that they created. They are not allowed to add names or vocabulary to any of the controlled name attribute lists or classification schema.</p></dd>
  <dt><b>Release Flag Administrator</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may modify the value of the <i>Release Flag</i> field for any item record. The <i>Release Flag</i> field is a default metadata field that controls whether item records are publicly viewable. This privilege flag can be used in tandem with or distinct from the <i>Resource Administrator</i> privilege flag, depending on the desired workflow.</p></dd>
  <dt><b>System Administrator</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may control the overall management and configuration of the site. They may not remove this privilege flag from their accounts, which is meant to prevent them from accidentally making it impossible to manage or configure the site.</p></dd>
  <dt><b>User Account Administrator</b></dt>
  <dd><p>Users with this privilege flag may view, edit, and delete registered user accounts. They may not remove this privilege flag from their own accounts, which is meant to prevent them from accidentally making it impossible to manage user accounts.</p></dd>
</dl>]]>
		</Content>
    	<CleanURL>help/users/user_access_privilege_flags</CleanURL>
    </Resource>

</ResourceCollection>
